Guide to the San Francisco Poster Brigade poster collection, 1974-1982
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center
San Francisco Poster Brigade poster collection
1974-1982
C0500
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center
3.0 linear feet (1 folder)
The collection documents the work of the San Francisco Poster Brigade in the 1970 and early 1980s. The poster measure from 14.5x11 inches to 22x18 inches.
San Francisco Poster Brigade.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchased in 2015.
Scope and Content
The collection documents the work of the San Francisco Poster Brigade in the 1970 and early 1980s. The subjects include worker and labor struggles, international conflict, and advertisements for art festivals. The international subjects include South Africa apartheid, fascism in Chile, and political prisoners in Spain. The poster measure from 14.5x11 inches to 22x18 inches.
Historical Information
The San Francisco Poster Brigade, originally called the Wilfred Owen Brigade, was begun by artist Rachael Romero and Leon Klayman in the San Francisco Bay area in 1975. In 1980 they began the Internationalist Art Show: Anti WW3, a mail-art phenomenon in San Francisco. The show became a festival of art, poetry, dance and performance, travelling to Los Angeles, Tucson, New York City and back to San Francisco until 1982.
Arrangement
Organized by subject.
Related Material
Special Collections Research Center holds other poster collections with political subject matter including the and the.
Index Terms
Document Types:
Political posters
Contents List
- San Francisco Poster Brigade posters
  - Internationalist Arts Festival, May 1982 (Box 1)
  - Defend Human Right is Chile, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 1)
  - Fascism in Chile, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 1)
  - Freedom for Political Prisoners, circa September 1976 (Box 1)
  - Anti-WW3, 1980 (Box 1)
  - And the worker, they claim, are content, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Condemn the South African Apartheid Regime, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 1)
  - Del Monte Profits from Apartheid, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 1)
  - Mayday, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 1)
  - Paul Robeson, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Bob Marley, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 1)
  - Iran Day, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 1)
  - Fight for the International Hotel, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 1)
  - Resisting War in the 80's, May 1981 (Box 1)
  - Pluck 'em, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Internationalist Art, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Victory to the Freedom Fighters of Southern Africa, July 1977 (Box 1)
  - Boycott Nestlé, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 1)
  - Anti-WW3, March/April 1981 (Box 1)
  - Freedom for Political Prisoners in Spain, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 1)
  - Terrorism, 1981 (Box 1)
  - The Uprising at Fuente Ovejuna, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Support the Struggle of Australian Aborigines, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 1)
  - Galeria de la Raza, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 1)
  - Political Poster Show, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Stop Forced Sterilization, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 1)
  - International Hotel Struggle, February 1979 (Box 1)
  - International Workers Day, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 1)
  - Revolución, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Free Skyhorse and Mohawk, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 1)
  - It's Raining in Zimbabwe, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 1)
  - International Workers Day, May Day, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Internationalist Art Show Anti-WW3, July 1981 (Box 1)
  - Stop Forced Drugging, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 1)
  - Pablo Neruda, 1976 (Box 1)